Guide to the Seaman Family Papers 1761-1983 (bulk 1830-1923) MS 552
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Business and Financial Documents, 1813-1923
  - Notebook Van Horn *, Undated (Volume Unknown container 609 for instance of Notebook Van Horn *)
  - Notebook * (Financial Notes - Amounts Paid), 1882-1884 (Volume Unknown container 610 for instance of Notebook * (Financial Notes - Amounts Paid))
  - Account Book John B. Seaman, 1866-1883 (Volume Unknown container 611 for instance of Account Book John B. Seaman)
  - The Merchant's and Seaman's Expeditious Measurer George W. Seaman *, 1884 (Volume Unknown container 612 for instance of The Merchant's and Seaman's Expeditious Measurer George W. Seaman *)
  - Ledger Book David Brown Co. -- George W. Seaman *, 1913-1923 (Volume Unknown container 613 for instance of Ledger Book David Brown Co. -- George W. Seaman *)
  - Stock Certificates, 1916-1919 (Volume Unknown container 614 for instance of Stock Certificates)
  - Letterbook / Business Correspondence *, 1918-1923 (Volume Unknown container 615 for instance of Letterbook / Business Correspondence *)
  - Stock Book and Ledger (used as Order Book), 1919-1920 (Volume Unknown container 616 for instance of Stock Book and Ledger (used as Order Book))
- Series VII. Personal Papers and Miscellany, 1805-1983, undated
  Personal papers and ephemera are included in this series. Of particular note is the wedding book of George Williams Seaman and Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman in which many of the family members are mentioned (Box 6, Folder 6). The folder also contains wedding invitations and several associated photographs. A portion of the estate inventory of George and Irmingarde (Box 6, Folder 7) is annotated to indicate from whom items were inherited or purchased.
  In Folder 8 are a number of items that are not clearly associated with a specific member of the Van Horn, Freeman, DeWindt or Seaman families. Items include letters; receipts; notes on scraps of paper; an advertisement for "Dr. Wistar's Balsom of Wild Cherry" (1844); extracts from a memorial for John Dubois (1869); pages from a notebook concerning medical expenses (1880-1881); a copy of a document promising freedom to two slaves if they obey their master for ten years (1805); and an undated sermon discussing Acts II Verse 23.
  Three volumes are included in the series - a notebook that appears to have belonged to Ida Van Horn Freeman and two scrapbooks belonging to Caroline Elizabeth DeWindt Monell. One scrapbook contains miscellaneous clippings and personal writings and the other includes, primarily, clippings describing Newburgh's Centennial (1882) celebrating the 100th anniversary of the end of the American Revolution. Caroline Monell's second husband, Judge John J. Monell, was on the Centennial's Executive Committee and made a speech during the festivities. The scrapbook also contains a drawing and other items unrelated to the Centennial. The smaller two volumes are housed in boxes (*).
  - Nameplate Henry V. Freeman, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Diary Pages [Ida L. Van Horn Freeman], 1897-1898 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Calendars, Calling Cards Irmingarge Van Horne Freeman Seaman, 1902-1903, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Essays and Poetry Gertrude Van Horn, 1865-1868 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Poem [Emma L. Freeman], Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Wedding Book George Williams and Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Estate Inventory George Williams and Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Van Horn, Freeman, DeWindt, Seaman, 1805-1907, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Notebook [Ida Van Horn Freeman] *, 1884-1890 (Volume Unknown container 617 for instance of Notebook [Ida Van Horn Freeman] *)
  - Scrapbook Caroline Elizabeth DeWindt Monell *, 1860-1893, undated (Volume Unknown container 618 for instance of Scrapbook Caroline Elizabeth DeWindt Monell *)
  - Scrapbook C.E. DeWindt Monell, 1876 - 1883, 1933, 1983 (Volume Unknown container 619 for instance of Scrapbook C.E. DeWindt Monell)
- Series VIII. Printed Matter and Photographs, 1858-1970, undated
  This series contains a variety of printed and visual materials. There are photographs (Box 6, Folder 9), including one of Amelia Seaman, wife of John B. Seaman. Among the other printed items are illustrations; advertisements; flyers; business cards; a 1901 schedule for the Lackawanna Railroad's New York - Buffalo - Chicago - St. Louis service (Box 6, Folder 12); the 1871 Annual Report of New York's Metropolitan Savings Bank (Box 6, Folder 13); event programs including the Commencement Exercises of Bellevue Hospital Medical College, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 14); and a ticket stub from the Metropolitan Opera (Box 6, Folder 16). In Folder 15, the pamphlet titled "Names of Those Buried in the Union Cemetery at Middle Island, L.I., New York" contains burial locations and dates for many members of the Van Horn family.
  Newspaper sections and clippings are contained in Box 6, Folder 17. Among the clippings are many concerning the 1887 America's Cup race and other yachting news; the mention, in 1882, of a crayon portrait of Grover Cleveland done by Ida L. Van Horn Freeman; and an 1887 New York Herald article about an electric streetcar in Boston. There are larger newspaper sections from papers such as the New York Daily Witness (1858), The Home Journal (1875) and American Merchant (1881). An 1859 issue of Harper's Weekly contains several novel serializations including Book II Chapter VI of Charles Dickens' new novel A Tale of Two Cities.
  The final item in this series is a photographic plate. Its subject is a pen and ink sketch of the DeWindt Homestead. The home was destroyed by fire c. 1892. Photographs from the plate were made for Irmingarde Van Horne Freeman Seaman.
  - Photographs, 1898-1910, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Illustrations, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Advertisements, Flyers, Cards, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lackawanna Railroad Schedule, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The Metropolitan Savings Bank of the City of New York Annual Report, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Programs, 1858-1873 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Names of Those Buried in the Union Cemetery at Middle Island, L. I., New York", 1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, 1900, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1858-1887 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Photographic Plate of the DeWindt Homestead, [1919] (Box Unknown container 620 for instance of Photographic Plate of the DeWindt Homestead)